Andrew J. Currie

andrew.j.currieO@gmail.com | 480-201-9948 | Lake Katrine, New York LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewjcurrieO/ | GitHub: https://github.com/curriecoderl Portfolio: https://curriecoder.github.io/portfolio-rev-1.1/

Summary

Software Engineer/Web Developer with a technical focus on quality. U.S. Army Veteran with a long standing passion for programming, recently graduated from UPenn LPS Coding Boot Camp. Equipped with an attention to detail that enables pixel-perfect front-end designs rendered from crude or sophisticated wireframes. Experience with back-end MySQL, NoSQL, Mongoose, Heroku technologies and in leading teams to achieve goals.

Technical Skills

Frontend: HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Javascript, Bootstrap, Materialize, Bulma, AJAX, SASS

Backend: MySQL, MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, Node, Handlebars, Webpack

Projects

Chessmate | https://github.com/curriecoder/Chessmate | https://mighty-ravine-90150.herokuapp.com/Front-end, Back-end, Lead Developer

- An app for chess enthusiasts to practice their craft, and better their game.
- Chessmate allows users to take their chess performance to the next level through challenging puzzles and a collection of resources to study. Familiar with all of the technologies used in order to troubleshoot bugs in deployment/production environments.
- Tools/Languages: Chessgrounds, LiChess API, React.js, Express, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Heroku

Project Management Application | https://github.com/curriecoder/project-management-application | https://stormy-fortress-72998.herokuapp.com/ | Back-end, Front-end | https://stormy-fortress-72998.herokuapp.com/

- This application allows users to network and manage projects with definitive timelines.
- Project Management Application accomplishes the goal of getting people together in order to work on a
 project collectively. The app allows users to create a profile, connect with other users, and plan projects
 with sub tasks to be completed. Responsibilities in this team were building the database models and
 seeding the database as well as handling the front-end design within the CSS framework Bulma.
- Tools/Languages: Node.js, Express.js, Sequelize, MySQL, MySQL 2, dotenv, bcrypt, express-session, express-handlebars, connect-session-sequelize, nodemon, materialize, day.js.

Pack Rat | https://github.com/curriecoder/Pack-Rat | https://nazikbestcoder.github.io/Pack-Rat/Lead Design, UX/UI Engineer, Lead Developer

- Pack Rat is an application for the prepared traveler with it's comprehensive list of national parks and packing checklist.
- This project accomplishes preparing users for the weather, terrain, and required packing for any venture
 into the United States Parks. Responsible for building the wire frame design and pitching the applicationconcept for approval. As the Lead Developer on this project, working with the team to determine
 individual strengths in order to complete the project by the deadline.

Tools/Languages: Bulma CSS Framework, OpenWeatherMap, NPS API, NASA API, jQuery, HTML.

Work Experience

Working Solutions

Feb 2021 - Current

Remote

Connection Specialist

- Professionally represent clients of Working Solutions as a remote contractor supporting live customer-consumer relationships.
- Carefully keep all sensitive personal information secure in accordance with applicable federal laws.
- Constantly communicating with resource agents to ensure company SOP is always followed.

Happy Currie Studios

Oct 2019 - Oct 2020

Music Producer/Primary Sound Engineer

Ashland, OR

- Accurately interpret customers' requests as appropriate actions within a digital audio workspace.
- Resourcefully located appropriate distribution network for product dispersal adhering to the set budget.
- Smoothly conducted daily operations of prepping musicians as well as recording/producing of all audio files.

Southern Oregon University

Nov 2018 - Oct 2019

Ashland, OR

Music Performance Student

- Routinely communicate with campus staff in order to secure assistance when required.
- Thoughtfully asked clarifying questions to improve the usability of the lesson presented.
- Successfully passed all classes taken while attending Southern Oregon University.

Agave Restaurant

May 2018 - Nov 2018

Prep Cook/Sanitation QA

Ashland, OR

- Punctually arrive in order to open facilities to ensure access to all vital products and equipment.
- Awarded by management for reducing breakage costs for the establishment.
- Carefully create an effective process for handling customer traffic flow to maintain optimal workflow.

Sabbatical Jun 2016 - May 2018

- Continued education at Mesa Community college
- Crafted business models for small scale private businesses
- Practiced botanical and agricultural skillset

Boeing Aerospace

May 2015 - May 2016

Overhaul Technician

Phoenix, AZ

- Routinely updated management facing metrics for production control.
- Efficiently performed repairs to accomplish deadlines in a high stress environment.
- Succeeded in implementing the first red/green discrepancy reporting in an excel program.

AeroturbineFeb 2014 - Nov 2015Aircraft Repair TechnicianPhoenix, AZ

 Routinely accomplished inspections and maintenance on aircraft going into storage as well as returning to service.

- Skillfully utilizing differences present on a maintenance team to accomplish the task at hand.
- Awarded the nickname 'Squirrel' by supervisors for my tenacity and small stature.

Honeywell Aerospace

Jul 2013 - Feb 2014

Flow-line Assembly Technician

Phoenix, AZ

- Consistently accomplished work with no supervision in a timely manner in order to meet production goals.
- Regularly coordinate with the production control department to ensure that all materials issued were in an acceptable condition.
- Achieved a personal acceptance rate of 100% for all assemblies tested.

Nabtesco Aerospace

Feb 2013 - Jun 2013

Research and Development Technician

Seattle, WA

- Closely working with electrical and mechanical engineers to develop an automated testing system for critical hydraulic systems.
- Awarded with bonus compensation for contributions to the manufacturing department while waiting for equipment.
- Strictly adhere to all safety guidelines as the work environment was extremely dangerous (pressures in excess of 4,000 psi).

Boeing Aerospace

May 2011 - Nov 2012

Overhaul Technician Phoenix, AZ

- Constantly working together with Quality Assurance to deliver the best product possible.
- Efficiently performed repairs on parts of various compositions to include: aluminum, magnesium, composite, etc.
- Succeeded in every instructional course given over a wide variety of subjects.

United States Army

Sep 2006 - Nov 2011

Aircraft Powerplant Repairer

Phoenix, AZ/Abroad

- Successfully maintained a fleet of aircraft in a combat environment (fast-paced, high-stress).
- Awarded the Army Service Award as well as Army Commendation Awards for outstanding performance.
- Meticulously maintained all aircraft records in digital format, improving visibility for all maintenance.

Education

University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA Full Stack Web Developer Certificate Nov 2021

• Nominated Keynote Speaker for performance during boot camp.

Arizona State University East Nov 2013

FAA Airframe & Powerplant License

• Self educated to gain license through university

United States Army Aviation Logistics School

Aircraft Powerplant Repairer Certificate

• Graduated with honors

Apr 2007